<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Node Oracle Glory on Dan Gillis</title><link>https://gilcrest.github.io/posts/archive/node-oracle-glory/</link><description>Recent content in Node Oracle Glory on Dan Gillis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 14:02:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gilcrest.github.io/posts/archive/node-oracle-glory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Path to node.js and Oracle Glory - Volume 3</title><link>https://gilcrest.github.io/posts/archive/node-oracle-glory/volume-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 14:02:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://gilcrest.github.io/posts/archive/node-oracle-glory/volume-3/</guid><description>Next step - node.js setup on Ubuntu. This was remarkably easy! I went to https://nodejs.org/ and viewed their Downloads section, where I then went to &amp;ldquo;Installing from package managers&amp;rdquo;. That link takes you to this URL on GitHub. If you read the first line of &amp;ldquo;Debian and Ubuntu based Linux distributions&amp;rdquo;, you&amp;rsquo;ll note you should go to nodesource&amp;rsquo;s blog post for the most up to date instructions. I did what I was told - read what they have to say on the page - helpful stuff!</description></item><item><title>My Path to node.js and Oracle Glory - Volume 2</title><link>https://gilcrest.github.io/posts/archive/node-oracle-glory/volume-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 11:25:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://gilcrest.github.io/posts/archive/node-oracle-glory/volume-2/</guid><description>OK, so now having established my database server in Volume 1 of this series, I now need to move to the next step - setting up my chromebook with Linux in order to facilitate node.js development. I chose a chromebook as my dev machine of choice as I wanted something that natively runs on Linux, but didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pay as much as a Mac and didn&amp;rsquo;t really like the Linux based machine options out there&amp;hellip; Google is doing a great job with these and after having my chromebook for a little over a week - I have to say I love it&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>My Path to node.js and Oracle Glory - Volume 1</title><link>https://gilcrest.github.io/posts/archive/node-oracle-glory/volume-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 20:33:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://gilcrest.github.io/posts/archive/node-oracle-glory/volume-1/</guid><description>I am starting a new personal project with the following goals in mind:
Learn JavaScript (I&amp;rsquo;m a beginner, but been reading/implementing for a while) Learn node.js Create a RESTful API using node.js calling a remote database server using Oracle&amp;rsquo;s node driver (node-oracledb) API should be simple to understand API in the backend should use the HR sample schema When using node.js, goal is to form a service request object in javascript and pass that object to a stored procedure in Oracle as an IN parameter, the same stored procedure should return a response object that will be parsed in javascript and the results displayed DISCLAIMER - When I actually have free time to develop - I am primarily a PL/SQL developer &amp;ndash; I love PL/SQL - there I said it!</description></item></channel></rss>